Hey guys, welcome to the another video, so we are in the advanced level, previous video
we have seen the EDR bypass and antivirus bypass through a hooking mechanism, and in this
video we are going to touch the uncrooking method and we will be discussing about the program
and how this will be going to happen, and what was happening in the back and reach and
everything we can discuss here, I will give you each and every program, every programs
which I have used, compilers, commands, the AES encryption based program, the shellcode I will be
giving everything to you in the GitHub repository, so you can utilize that and you can use it
for your test environment, but before moving on to the discussion I will be giving you
one, I will be telling you one thing, so this course is completed design for legal and ethical
hacking purpose, the programs we discussed in our course, it was completely belongs
to the exploitation, and advanced exploitation in Viron Monday, even the same program
was used by the protectors to do some kind of malicious task in the environment, so you
need to be very care about this kind of applications and this kind of tools which we are
using in the real world, okay, so again I am saying this course is completely designed
for only an educational purpose, not in terms to design for any kind of exploitation in
the around the globe, okay, so if you need to test this code you can run it in your environment
if you do not use it in the global corporate environment or any other machine, okay, so
let us jump on to the unhooking method, so we know what is of hooking, how we will be
hooking, we discussed about the detors and how it going to happen, I already said EDR will
be also hooking the same method, so what we discussed in the previous video, so if you
need to bypass the hooking mechanism from the EDR, the way we can do the time we can
say it is called as an unhooking, okay, EDR hook their deal into the process, so what we
are going to do, we are going to unhook the DLL from the process, let me show you an
example of the process, example from the process explorer, to the task host like yesterday's
then we can, okay, I will be able to do that, I will be able to do that, I will be able to
do that, and we can see, so let us see any kind of process, whether that was hook by our
anti-virus software, here you can see the task host.exe hooked by the b-defender anti-virus
software, so it was also of the method from the anti-virus software, and EDR will hook
their own DLL into the process, okay, so basically the EDR will be targeting the NDDL,
so if anything, any call has been happened, any function call has been happened from the
NDDL process NDDL library function, it will be, the EDR will be start hooking the, hooking
the NDDL API calls, okay, so in the previous video we have discussed with a lot of examples
like how the EDR will be hook, when the EDR will be hook, the process, so in this video
we can see how we can un-hook that, okay, how we can un-hook that, so I already said EDR
will be targeting the NDDL application, so NDDL based library function, so if the, if the
application loads NDDL library, and it was calling some NDDL functions like right file
of NDDL file of, it will be start hooking the API function, right, so we know the only,
so EDR targeting NDDL libraries, and it was hooking the EDR based program, okay, so our
assumption is, so what if, what if we un-hooked the NDDL library from the process, did you
get that point, so what if I un-hooked the NDDL, I just removed the NDDL library from my
process, okay, so now EDR unable to hook my process again, right, so EDR doesn't know
how to hook, because there is no NDDL library was there, okay, so let me go into depth,
okay, so if you remove, if you remove the NDDL library from the process, your application
will get failed, because your application mandatory needs NDDL libraries to do some task,
okay, so every process has a NDDL library, here you can see NDDL library was there, so
if I remove this NDDL library from this application, so this application will get failed,
and my system will get stuck, okay, so the application needs a NDDL library, so what we
can do, okay, so the thing we can do, we can un-hook the NDDL library, and we can load
the fresh NDDL library from the disk, okay, so we can un-hook the current NDDL library, okay,
DLL library file, and we can load another NDDL library from the disk, a fresh copy of NDDL
library from the disk, okay, so now the EDR doesn't know what's happening in the background,
because the EDRs will only hook once the application gets initiated the NDDL library, once
the application was started and it was initiating the NDDL library, it was loading
an NDDL library, at that point the EDR will hook their DLLs or their code into the process,
so now we are removing the hook NDDL library and we loading the fresh copy of NDDL library
from the disk, so now EDR doesn't know, so what's happening, the EDR, you're thinking like
I hooked the NDDL that was there and nothing happening inside the process, but the EDDL
doesn't know, we will be replacing the NDDL library with the fresh copy, okay, so that
is called as the fresh copy NDDL library API unhooking, so in this video I just explained
the theory what will be happening in the backend, so the next video we will be discussing
about the program and how this will going to happen, so this is one of an advanced techniques,
so this will be many might feel this could be a difficult technique, difficult to understand,
but if you have any questions just reach out to me in the question and answer session,
and I'll answer the questions in 24, I'll try to answer the question in 24 hours of time,
yeah, so that will be the overall explanation of what we are going to do, okay, so every
program, every compiler commands, I'll be giving in the GitHub repo, so don't worry about
that, we'll be getting each and everything which what I'm going to use, okay, so let's hop
off from here and we'll discuss the program and execution section in the next video, thank
you, bye-bye.